so thank you for attending this
非常感谢您参加
presentation not quite as early as
演讲还不及早
Stuart's presentation earlier actually
斯图尔特的演讲实际上早些时候
curiously how many people were in
奇怪的是有多少人
Stuart's presentation earlier today so
斯图尔特今天早些时候的演讲
okay quite a few so we can compare notes
好吧，所以我们可以比较笔记
afterwards okay so there's the
之后好吧，所以有
obligatory legal statement so what am I
强制性法律声明，我是什么
going to talk today about today so I'm
今天要谈论今天，所以我
gonna do a bit of a recap on the
要回顾一下
unmodifiable collections in the JDK just
JDK中无法修改的集合
to say what we have there at the moment
说我们现在有什么
I'm gonna give a brief overview of
我将简要概述
immutable collections in external Java
外部Java中的不可变集合
libraries and JVM based platforms and
库和基于JVM的平台以及
then I'm going to talk about immutable
那我要谈一谈不可变
collections leveraging persistent data
利用持久数据进行收集
structures so when I refer to
结构，所以当我指的是
persistence I do not mean database in
持久性我不是说数据库在
any way whatsoever or persisting to
任何方式或坚持
non-volatile memory or any of those
非易失性存储器或任何这些
things it's a very confusing term but
事情这是一个非常令人困惑的术语，但是
persistence is sometimes easier to
持久性有时更容易
understand than immutable when people
当人们理解时，了解比不改变
hear mutable and immutable and they
听到易变和一成不变，他们
can't differentiate between the two so
不能区分两者，所以
sometimes people refer to these as
有时人们称这些为
persistent collections rather than
持久性集合而不是持久性集合
immutable collections so when I refer to
不可变的集合，所以当我提到
these immutable collections I'm making
我正在做的这些不可变的收藏
no claims whatsoever as to the
没有任何关于
immutability of the collections element
集合元素的不变性
so I'm not talking about immutability in
所以我不是在谈论不可变性
the large in the language or forcing
语言或强迫的大
immutability all the way down deeply
永恒不变
into these structures I'm just talking
这些结构我只是在说
about the collection structures
关于收集结构
themselves this is a huge bike shed area
本身，这是一个巨大的自行车棚
you can talk about this for months and
你可以谈论这个几个月
months and months and months so I'm just
几个月又几个月，所以我只是
trying to arrange sort of enclose the
试图安排一些封闭
scope in just two collections for this
为此仅在两个集合中
for this talk so as there is a huge set
这个演讲有很多
of advantages to being immutable I think
我认为优势是一成不变的
the first fit occurs to me is if I don't
最适合我的是如果我不这样做
have to think about data racers I'm a
必须考虑数据竞赛者，我是
happy person if I have to think about
快乐的人，如果我必须考虑
data racers I get a headache it's if
数据赛车手我很头疼
you're dealing with concurrent stuff and
你正在处理并发的东西
you know that what you're dealing with
你知道你在处理什么
is immutable you can safely trust that
是一成不变的，您可以放心地相信
and you can understand that and that's a
你可以理解，那是一个
lot clearer but having to deal with
更清晰，但必须处理
sometimes with data races and the
有时是数据竞赛和
headaches and debugging that actually
头痛和调试实际上
that that's a huge advantage it's also
那是一个巨大的优势
if you have things for their immutable
如果你有他们一成不变的东西
and are trusted to be immutable you know
并且相信你一成不变
that nothing else can scratch on them
别无他物
either on purpose maliciously or by
故意或恶意
accident and that's a nice property as
意外，这是一个很好的财产
well so if a library that you're using
好吧，如果您正在使用的图书馆
uses these data structures you know you
使用您知道的这些数据结构
can trust this library and they have a
可以信任这个图书馆，他们有一个
bunch of properties in terms of
一堆属性
optimization they're effectively
优化它们是有效的
constant so that gives a lot of
常数，因此
opportunities for the rajah the run time
拉贾运行时间的机会
hotspot to optimize these things and
热点来优化这些东西
treat them as constants in line and our
将它们视为符合常量的常量，我们
constant fold them when generating when
当生成时不断折叠它们
hotspot generates hot hot little bits of
热点会产生热点
code that are optimized and they're also
经过优化的代码，它们也是
had properties that you can optimize
具有可以优化的属性
these things in the java implementations
Java实现中的这些东西
over space and time if you have a small
如果你有一个小的空间和时间
collection you can choose to use a
您可以选择使用
different data structure and if you have
不同的数据结构，如果有
a large collection and Stewart Marx did
大量收藏，斯图尔特·马克思做了
some of these kinds of optimizations for
这些优化中的一些
his collections list off set of map
他的收藏列出了地图集
table for smaller collections were more
较小收藏的桌子更多
optimized they save space they trade-off
优化它们节省了权衡
some space versus time and you can do
一些空间和时间，你可以做
these types of tricks with even when you
这些技巧，即使你
have immutability and your collections
具有不变性和您的收藏
so this is my wish list for immutable
所以这是我一成不变的愿望清单
collections if I were going to do this
收藏，如果我要这样做
in the JDK which is no this is no
在JDK中，这不是吗？
commitment to doing this in the JDK but
致力于在JDK中做到这一点，但
if I were going to do it this has been
如果我要去做的话
this would be my wish list here so I
这就是我的愿望清单，所以我
think the first one to me is if you're
认为我的第一个是
coding using immutable collections I'd
使用不可变的集合进行编码
like to see that in the type name I'd
希望看到我输入的类型名称
like to see that in the API so when I
想在API中看到它，所以当我
read the code I know this thing is
阅读代码，我知道这件事是
immutable I have to treat it differently
不变的，我必须区别对待
to say list or map if it was a mutable
说出列表或地图是否可变
list or a mutable map I can treat that
列表或可变的地图我可以治疗
differently I know it has a different
我知道它有不同的地方
API I know I have to consider this
我知道我必须考虑这个API
slightly differently when the way I use
我使用的方式略有不同
my algorithms or a I develop my
我的算法或我开发我的算法
algorithms incidentally has anyone
算法顺带有人
programmed in closure at all whew
完全关闭编程
it's kind of mind-bending because it it
这有点弯腰，因为它
is totally a new table for the most part
在大多数情况下完全是一张新桌子
and the
和
it's kind of mind-bending at first if
首先，如果
you use used to the mute mutable way not
你习惯了静音可变的方式
in you to a beautiful way of coding your
以一种优美的方式编码您的
algorithms tend to change and I think
算法趋于改变，我认为
that's it's worth actually experimenting
这是值得实际尝试的
with languages like Clojure and Haskell
使用Clojure和Haskell等语言
to see how you can code in immutable
看看如何在不可变的代码
ways rather than immutable ways or pyth
方式，而不是不变的方式或pyth
it really changes the way you think
它确实改变了您的思维方式
sometimes these collections I think
我认为有时候这些收藏
should be sealed and what I mean by that
应该被密封，我的意思是
is only trusted parties can actually
只有受信任的各方才能真正
extend these collections so I wouldn't
扩展这些集合，这样我就不会
want to let anyone else extend my Anu
想让其他人扩展我的阿努
tuple list because I don't trust them I
元组列表，因为我不信任他们
don't trust them to do it properly I
我不相信他们做得很好
don't trust them either because they're
也不要相信他们，因为他们是
there being a black hat or a white hat
有黑帽子或白帽子
in terms of what their motives are or
根据他们的动机是
because they've made mistakes we've had
因为他们犯了我们的错误
this with our own collections in the JDK
这与我们在JDK中的收藏
they're open and we have to write
他们是开放的，我们必须写
defensive code against incorrect
防御代码不正确
collections people who have extended
扩展了收藏的人
ArrayList people have extended hashmap
ArrayList人们扩展了hashmap
and so forth like that we don't
诸如此类，我们不
necessarily do the right thing I want
一定做我想做的正确的事
needs to be closed and only we can
需要关闭，只有我们可以
implement them and then we can guarantee
实施它们，然后我们可以保证
the immutability of these things I would
这些东西的永恒性
like them to provide a bridge to the
像他们一样为
mutable collections so you have to opt
可变集合，因此您必须选择
in and say to lists or to mutable lists
在列表或可变列表中说
rather than extending from list if you
而不是从列表扩展
extend from list then you can easily
从列表扩展，然后您可以轻松地
pass it around to something that accepts
将其传递给可以接受的东西
list then it just becomes into the old
列表，然后它变成了旧的
collections mutable collections world
可变收藏品世界
where you might operate on it and do a
您可以在其中进行操作并执行
mutating operation get an exception I
变异操作异常
don't want that I want to explicitly
不想我想明确
something in the code that says to
代码中的某些内容
mutable list or something like so you
可变列表或类似的东西
really know when you're transitioning
真正知道您何时过渡
from the immutable to the mutable world
从不变到可变
and I want efficient construction
我想要高效的建筑
updates and copying so if I have a new
更新和复制，所以如果我有一个新的
to the list and I add an element to it I
到列表中，然后向其中添加元素
want a new a mutable list but somehow
想要一个新的可变列表，但不知何故
underneath it shares a bit of structure
它的下面有一些结构
between the previous collection and the
在上一个集合和
new collection so we can save some space
新的收藏，所以我们可以节省一些空间
maybe trade off some time and save some
也许要权衡一些时间并节省一些
space but we get structural sharing
空间，但我们得到结构共享
underneath and we can do efficient forms
在下面，我们可以做高效的表格
of copying I want a way to build these
复制我想要一种构建这些的方法
collections up in a confined mutable way
以有限的可变方式收集
and then
接着
freeze and say now your immutable I may
冻结，然后说你一成不变的我可能
forget time to show you some stuff what
忘记时间给你看一些东西
we're doing there on that so that's my
我们在那里做，那是我的
wish list I guess you could describe
愿望清单，我想你可以形容
them as goals if we formalize them a bit
如果我们将其正式化，将它们作为目标
more so what have we got in the JDK so
还有更多，我们在JDK中得到了什么
the JDK has a notion of unmodifiable
JDK有一个不可修改的概念
collections everyone know what they are
每个人都知道它们是什么
you've used these things before so
你以前用过这些东西
unmodifiable is a runtime property of a
不可修改的是
collection so if you have an
集合，所以如果你有一个
unmodifiable collection the modifying
不可修改的集合
methods like add put remove throw
诸如add put remove throw之类的方法
unsupported operation exception and
不支持的操作异常和
there's no way to directly query this
没有办法直接查询这个
and you might ask why would you want to
你可能会问为什么要
directly query it well you might want to
直接查询它，您可能想要
know if you need to make a copy or not
知道是否需要复印
if you've got a list how do you know
如果您有清单，您怎么知道
it's unmodifiable well you could do an
这是无法修改的，你可以做一个
instance of an and looks at some
的实例，然后看一些
internal JDK Corrections but I wouldn't
内部JDK更正，但我不会
recommend that so if we wanted to add an
建议，如果我们想添加一个
efficient copy method to the JDK we
高效的复制方法到我们的JDK
can't actually do this and let third
不能真正做到这一点，让第三
parties opt in if they're going to opt
各方选择是否要加入
into that
进入那个
unmodifiable view as well for example
例如，不可修改的视图
guava which I'll get onto in a moment so
番石榴，我稍后再讲
non modifier your wrapper is essentially
非修饰符，您的包装器本质上是
a source to a backing collection so you
支持集合的来源，因此您
you've all done this collections dot and
你们都已经完成了这个收藏
modify the list source list so if the
修改列表来源列表，以便
source list is modified it will be
源列表被修改，它将是
reflected in your wrapper as well so
也反映在您的包装中
they're not really immutable things in
它们并不是真正不变的东西
this notion here it's just what you get
这就是你所得到的
back is an unmodifiable view over your
背面是您无法修改的视图
source and you can have directly
来源，您可以直接拥有
unmodifiable as well with the list of so
列表也无法修改
if you there's there's no source here
如果你那里没有资料
that you can observe or see you're just
你可以观察或看到你只是
creating a collection kind of like a
创建一个像
collection literal in a language and
语言集合文字和
you're getting back an unmodifiable list
您将获得一个无法修改的列表
back so how do you get immutability with
回来，那么你如何获得不变性
these things well usually what you do is
这些事情通常你要做的是
you do the unmodifiable list you clone
你做了你无法修改的清单
it because you don't know where the
因为你不知道在哪里
source is unmodifiable or not you have
来源无法修改，或者您没有
to take a clone a copy and then you wrap
克隆一个副本然后包裹
it and then you throw away the source I
它，然后你扔掉我的来源
don't want a reference to that because I
不想提及，因为我
don't I don't want to know what that is
不，我不想知道那是什么
I don't want to modify that at
我不想在
or another way to do that is using
或另一种方法是使用
stream so you can use color collect
流，因此您可以使用颜色收集
collecting then two less than then wrap
然后收集少于两个的包裹
it in a list there and I'm throwing away
它在列表中，我扔掉了
the source implicitly here so it's not
源隐含在这里，所以不是
going to be reference from outside
将会被外界参考
anymore
不再
and of course list of and friends are as
当然还有和的列表是
if the source is never accessible so
如果源永远无法访问，那么
that's the way I kind of describe a
我就是这样描述一个
modifiable collections to myself and you
可修改的收藏给我自己和你
have to jump through hoops if you want
如果你想的话，必须跳过篮球
to get something that's immutable and
得到一些不变的东西
you knows immutable but it's not
你知道一成不变，但事实并非如此
reflected in the type system and so
反映在类型系统中等等
forth like that so if I go back to my
这样的话，所以如果我回到我的
wish list and look at the JDK
愿望清单，看看JDK
collections but they're not doing very
集合，但他们做得并不好
well here there's no types to indicate
好吧，这里没有类型来表示
that you've got an immutable thing it's
你有一个不变的东西
not sealed you can open it up
没有密封就可以打开
tautologically it provides a bridge to
在重言式上，它为
itself and there's not really any
本身，实际上没有任何东西
efficient construction updates and
高效的施工更新和
copying if you get a list and you want
复制，如果你有一个列表，你想
to make sure that no one scribbles on it
确保没有人在上面涂鸦
you have to take a copy and if you want
你必须要复印，如果你想
when you return it you even make a copy
当您退还它时，您甚至会复制一份
you you wrap it and hold the source to
你把它包裹起来并把源保存到
yourself tightly so no one else can get
紧紧地绑住自己，这样没人能得到
it so I think unmodified there's a
所以我认为没有修改
reasonable extraction abstraction for
合理的提取抽象
mutable collections but it's not really
可变的集合，但不是真的
good for immutable sorry did I say
有益于一成不变，对不起，我说
mutable or immutable I'm going to fixed
可变或不变的，我要解决
up so good abstraction for mutable
很好的可变性抽象
collections but not for immutable
集合，但并非一成不变
collections there that would be my
那里的收藏将是我的
argument it doesn't mean we shouldn't
论据并不意味着我们不应该
improve this notion in the JDK but I
在JDK中改进了这个概念，但是我
think if you want to get to truly
想想如果你想真正地
immutable collections we have to have
我们必须拥有的不可变集合
something else so what does guavas
别的东西，番石榴怎么办
immutable collections do anyone use
任何人都可以使用不可变的集合
guavas collections they are really quite
番石榴的收藏，他们真的很
popular very well-designed
流行的精心设计
so guava has a bunch of sealed types
所以番石榴有很多密封类型
such as a mutable list and a mutable map
例如可变列表和可变映射
and these implement our corresponding
这些实现了我们相应的
JDK mutable collection types a mutable
JDK可变集合类型是可变的
list implements lists and copying is
list实现列表，复制是
kind of smart it knows the copy of if it
有点聪明，它知道副本是否
takes you of a collection and it will
带您去收集，它将
know whether it's an immutable list of
知道这是否是一成不变的清单
its own kind or not and decide to return
是否自己的，决定退货
it back or do a copy so in some sense
退回或复印，从某种意义上讲
it's kind of smart
有点聪明
whereas when we're doing the
而当我们在做
unmodifiable case or we're in the JDK
无法修改的案例，或者我们在JDK中
without these things we have to program
没有这些东西，我们必须编程
defensively and take off
防守并起飞
so I'd say that manifests immutability
所以我会说这是不变的
it's sealed it doesn't provide a bridge
它是密封的，没有提供桥梁
so you don't opt-in explicitly in sauce
所以你不会明确选择加入酱汁
it because it extends list you can pass
因为它扩展了您可以通过的列表
it around to something that accepts list
它周围的东西可以接受清单
I don't like that I'd prefer explicit
我不喜欢我更喜欢露骨
opt-in to know you're transitioning
选择加入以了解您正在过渡
between the two so it's sort of as soon
在两者之间，所以有点像
as you pop up to list you're in the
当您弹出列表时，您在
unmodifiable world again and it kind of
不可修改的世界再次
provides efficient completion copying a
提供有效的完成复制
bit of efficient construction through
通过一些有效的建设
builders but it's it's not what I like
建筑商，但这不是我想要的
they they're a good compromise they they
他们是一个很好的折衷他们
have some good properties with them but
与他们有一些好的特性，但
to me it doesn't go far enough
对我来说还远远不够
there's eclipse collections how many
有日食收藏有多少
have used these these are previously
以前用过这些
goldman-sachs collections this is I
高盛收藏这是我
described as something for everyone it's
被描述为每个人的东西
quite a cornucopia of various
各种的聚宝盆
collections out there and you may find
那里的收藏，你可能会发现
something very useful in these kind
在这种情况下非常有用的东西
doing these types of collections from
进行这些类型的收藏
what I what I've looked at here I'm not
我在这里看过的我不是
an expert on these collections they
这些收藏的专家
manifest immutability they are not
表现出不可变性
sealed they do provide a bridge as far
密封，他们确实提供了一座桥梁
as I can tell and they have similar
据我所知，他们有相似的
issues as guava does in terms of
番石榴的问题
efficient construction updates in
高效的建筑更新
copying so if I look at Vava previously
复制，所以如果我以前看过Vava
called Java slang people heard about
有人叫Java lang语
that nice functional library closure
不错的功能库关闭
Scala maybe Kotlin too but I'm not as
斯卡拉也可能是科特林，但我不是
familiar with Catalan I think these tick
熟悉加泰罗尼亚语，我认为这些勾
all the boxes all the goals or wish list
所有方框所有目标或愿望清单
that I had they often may manifest in
我经常看到他们
mutability they're sealed they provide a
他们被密封的可变性提供了
bridge and they also provide additional
桥梁，他们还提供其他
construction updates and copying I
施工更新和复制我
haven't verified this fully but that's
尚未完全验证，但这是
my gut feeling here and what these
我的直觉在这里以及这些
provide so let's look a bit closely at
提供，让我们仔细看看
the efficient updates so what is going
高效的更新，这是怎么回事
on here
在这
all these collections some of these
所有这些收藏中的一些
collections v's libraries or platforms
集合v的库或平台
provide leverage something called
提供杠杆作用
persistent data structures predominately
持久性数据结构
for map sets and vectors vectors are non
对于地图集和向量，向量不是
linked lists they're not Java util
链接列表，它们不是Java util
vector which should be deprecated
应弃用的向量
that possibly never removed is it
可能永远不会删除
deprecated already Stewart no no yeah
已弃用Stewart no no yeah
same for a hash-table as well so they
哈希表也一样，所以他们
they leverage something called and we
他们利用所谓的东西，我们
call persistent data structures so what
调用持久性数据结构
is a persistent data structure so absent
是一个持久的数据结构，所以不存在
data structure is something that
数据结构是
preserves a previous version of itself
保留自身的先前版本
where modified now you can easily write
现在修改的地方，您可以轻松编写
your own persistent straight data
您自己的持久性直接数据
structure by doing a copy-on-write
通过写时复制结构
that would be terribly inefficient and
那将是非常低效的，
that's what we have to do today to code
这就是我们今天要做的代码
defensively in the JDK but what these
在JDK中进行防御，但是这些
persistent data structures do they all
持久数据结构是否全部
have a common theme underneath and
在下面有一个共同的主题
that's called hash array map tries or
这就是所谓的哈希数组映射尝试或
ham tease for short and they are the
火腿短时间戏弄，他们是
basis of efficient persistent immutable
有效持久不变的基础
map sets and vectors so I think they use
地图集和向量，所以我认为它们使用
were pioneered in part by phil Bagwell
由菲尔·巴格韦（Philip Bagwell）率先开发
who worked in Scala and worked at
在Scala工作并在
typesafe and and I think like Bend and
Typesafe和我认为像Bend和
what she's passed away now but I think
她现在去世了，但我想
he he pioneered some of these
他他开创了其中一些
implementations and designs in Scala
Scala中的实现和设计
first of all what's good about these is
首先，这些的好处是
these allow you to provide structural
这些使您能够提供结构
sharing between the new and previous
新旧共享
version of a collection so they instead
集合的版本，因此他们改为
of taking the whole copy of something
拿东西的整个副本
you take a copy of only the bits that
您只复制了
you need to change and then you can
您需要进行更改，然后就可以
share the other bits and because it's
共享其他位，因为
immutable you know that those other bits
不可变，你知道那些其他的位
aren't going to get modified they are
不会被修改，他们是
effectively constant time effectively
有效地恒定时间
constant time bit of wiggle room here
恒定时间的摆动空间
for many operations and they can be
对于许多操作，他们可以
cached friendly as well so if you're
缓存友好，所以如果你是
traversing over them you're often
遍历他们，你经常
prefetching stuff from the cache and so
从缓存中预取东西等等
you get good good performance they won't
你会得到很好的表现，他们不会
beat something like a ray list ArrayList
击败诸如射线列表ArrayList之类的东西
is damn hard to beat but they trade-off
该死的很难击败，但他们要权衡
some performance for some structural
一些结构的性能
sharing so what's the basis of this if
分享，那么这的基础是什么
you know what a tri tree is I copied
你知道我复制了三棵树吗
this from Wikipedia so you can go to the
这个来自维基百科，所以你可以去
Wikipedia page instead if you want to so
如果您愿意的话，可以使用维基百科页面
this is an example of a tri tree so a
这是一个三叉树的例子
tri tree basically it stores a bit of
三叉树基本上存储了
the keys if you're making a map it
按键（如果正在制作地图）
stores a bit of a keys in each node
在每个节点中存储一些密钥
you go down so if in the example here
你下去，所以如果在这里的例子
you've got a try for keys a tutti Ted 10
您已经尝试过琴键Tedti 10
I in and in and then numbers for the
我在里面然后在数字
values so you basically traverse the
值，因此您基本上遍历了
tree saying oh t okay I go to this node
树说好吧，我去这个节点
and oh I go to two and so forth like
哦，我去了两个等等
that and you need to store a prefix of
那，你需要存储一个前缀
your keys in your tree for all of the
您的树中所有钥匙的钥匙
entries that you actually have so it's
您实际拥有的条目
quite an that it can be quite an
相当可以
efficient mechanism and data structure
高效的机制和数据结构
and often these kinds of data structures
通常是这类数据结构
use when you're when you're typing
键入时使用
something in and you do word completion
里面有东西，你做单词补全
you might be using a try underneath to
您可能在下面尝试
do to select the possible words that you
做选择您可能的单词
might want to complete against so
可能想完成反对
essentially a try here you have a you
本质上是一个尝试，你有一个你
have an alphabet here we have the
这里有一个字母，我们有
alphabet A to Z lower and uppercase and
字母A到Z小写和大写
you have a string and a string in this
你有一个字符串和一个字符串
case would be unbounded because it would
案件将不受限制，因为它将
just be a word but we can use the same
只是一个字，但我们可以使用相同的
techniques in hash array map tries so
哈希数组映射中的技术尝试这样
hash or a map try is essentially a
哈希或地图尝试本质上是
symbol instead of a letter of the
用符号代替字母
alphabet you can say it's a symbol of a
字母，你可以说这是一个符号
five bit sequence it's just a number
五位序列只是一个数字
from nought to 31 and you can say the
从零到31，你可以说
string is fixed in size of length 32
字符串的长度固定为32
bits consisting of seven symbols and
由七个符号和
just the last symbol is just truncated
只是最后一个符号被截断了
to two bits so the string in a hash
到两位，所以字符串在哈希中
array map tri is essentially the hash
数组映射tri本质上是哈希
code of an object which is the key so
对象的代码是关键
we're sort of laterally transforming a
我们正在横向转换一个
domain to a 32 bit string and chopping
域为32位字符串并切碎
it up into a little bit of symbols and
它变成了一些符号，
that's a sort of a symbols our alphabet
这是我们字母表中的一种符号
and a string is of fixed length of size
字符串长度固定
and if here's an example here so say we
如果这里有一个例子，那么说我们
had a hash code of cafe baby here and so
这里有一个咖啡馆婴儿的哈希码等等
our symbols will be going from right to
我们的符号将从右到右
left symbol one will be the first five
左符号将是前五个
bits symbol two will be the next five
位符号二将是下一个五
bits and so forth and so on down so we
等等等等，所以我们
have maximum of seven symbols
最多七个符号
essentially a tree depth of six does
本质上是六棵树
that make sense what you're doing is
知道你在做什么
taking five bits off each of a hash code
从每个哈希码中减去五位
so essentially we have wide branching
所以本质上我们有广泛的分支
factor here so each each node in our
这里的因素，所以我们每个节点
tree instead of if we go back here in a
树，而不是如果我们回到这里
tree each node without have a branching
树每个节点没有分支
factor of 32 and you go down for a depth
因数32
of 6 so the depth is actually controlled
6的深度，因此实际上可以控制
you're not going to go down like depth
你不会像深度一样沉下去
of 64 or 32 it's pretty pretty
64或32这很漂亮
constrained and it's effectively
受约束，并且有效
constant time for look at what I mean by
不断地看我的意思
effectively constant time if you're
有效地固定时间，如果你
going to do a lookup of a key and a
将要查找一个键和一个
value is essentially log 2n over 5 which
值本质上是5的log 2n
is almost o 1 you can say for most cases
在大多数情况下，您几乎可以说1
so these things provide good structural
所以这些东西提供了良好的结构
sharing I will show later on visually I
分享，稍后我会在视觉上显示
show some visualization of this
显示一些可视化
structural sharing to get this across
通过结构共享来解决这个问题
more I hope but because of this they're
我希望更多，但正因为如此，他们
good for updates they're also
很好的更新他们也
potentially good for merging and
潜在地有利于合并和
splitting so in our collection in our
在我们的收藏中分裂
streams when we do a parallel collection
我们进行并行收集时流
to say to list or to map potentially we
说可能列出或映射我们
could use these structures underneath do
可以在下面使用这些结构
more efficient merging than we currently
比我们目前更有效的合并
do today because we have a code it's
今天就做，因为我们有一个代码
actually a little bit inefficient what
实际上有点低效
we do when we do collect two lists in
我们在收集两个清单时会做
parallel or grouping by and these
与这些平行或分组
structures could be very interesting in
结构可能非常有趣
terms of allowing you to collect in
允许您收集的条款
parallel and then merge them efficiently
并行然后有效地合并它们
together because we know some structures
在一起，因为我们知道一些结构
are different in each part and some
每个部分都有所不同
structures are shared and we can do a
结构是共享的，我们可以做一个
little bit of merging just on the shared
只是在共享上进行一点点合并
bits they provide good memory usage as
它们提供了良好的内存使用
well which I hope to explain and good as
我希望能很好地解释
I said good cache coherency and this is
我说好的缓存一致性，这是
the basis for vectors that rich Hickey
丰富的Hickey载体的基础
coded in closure and where fill bag well
封闭式编码，装满袋的地方
also extended his research to look at
还扩大了他的研究范围
relaxed radix balanced trees for vectors
向量的松弛基数平衡树
and it can also be used for multi maps
它也可以用于多张地图
at JVM LS this year the presenter talked
在今年的JVM LS上，主持人谈到了
about how he could use these structures
关于他如何使用这些结构
for multi maps as well so the quite
对于多张地图也是如此
versatile and they can also be applied
用途广泛，也可以应用
to mutable collections as well and this
以及可变的收藏
is what interests me for efficient
我感兴趣的是高效
building of something before you turn it
在你转身之前建造东西
into something immutable and I think
变成一成不变的东西，我认为
they can be efficiently implemented in
它们可以在
Java they can be efficiently implemented
Java它们可以有效地实现
in Scala but actually Java I believe in
在Scala中，但实际上我相信Java
closures are actually Java
闭包实际上是Java
implementations and Vava is another
实现和Vava是另一个
example of these collections as well
这些集合的例子
being implemented so here's a real naive
被实施，所以这是一个真正的天真
implementation of how you might go about
实现您可能的工作方式
this CP map is a persistent map so I
这个CP图是一个持久图，所以我
have a thirty two way branching factor
有三十二分枝因子
and I'll have a key value I need to
我将拥有一个关键的价值
store my keys and values as entry so
将我的键和值存储为条目，以便
what I'm doing is they've got a node
我正在做的是他们有一个节点
here object array and I'm storing 64
这是对象数组，我要存储64
it's a site length of 64 key value key
网站长度为64个键值键
value key value key value and some of
值键值键值和一些
these entries might be null because the
这些条目可能为空，因为
value there might not be an entry
值可能没有条目
actually there and it might be a sub
实际上在那里，可能是一个子
layer there so if I look at the get
在那里分层，所以如果我看一下
method here for finding a value for a
这里找到一个值的方法
given key I might I want to ask what is
给定密钥，我可能想问一下
my symbol at my current depth so
我目前的深度
remember the symbols of the five bits
记住五位的符号
going across the hash code here so I've
在这里浏览哈希代码，所以我已经
got to say well how do I index into that
得说好我该如何索引
array of nodes well first of all I've
首先我要完成一系列的节点
got to get my symbol for my hash code
必须获得我的哈希码的符号
and essentially the method symbol at
本质上是方法符号
depth is there all it does a shift down
深度就是向下移动的全部
by the depth times five and chopped off
深度乘以五并砍掉
and get the first five bits that's it
并得到前五位
and that's my index into my array I look
这就是我对数组的索引
it up I see if it's a sub layer node I
我看看它是否是子层节点
Traverse down otherwise otherwise I see
往下走，否则我看到
if it's present and I return an optional
如果存在，我返回一个可选
say whether it's present or not know
说出它是否存在
that that's pretty simple but that's
那很简单，但那是
like 64 entries I might not have all 64
像64个条目，我可能没有全部64个条目
entries in there that's a pretty
里面的条目很漂亮
inefficient representation there so you
那里的代表效率很低，所以你
can do something better and what you can
可以做得更好，什么可以做
do is you can use a bitmap to express
你可以用位图来表达
which entries are present at my level in
在我的级别中存在哪些条目
my tree and I can have a number an array
我的树，我可以有一个数字数组
an object array of nose that contains is
包含的鼻子的对象数组是
of length of a number of bits set in my
我设置的位数的长度
bitmap so that's a more compressed
位图，这样可以更压缩
representation and that's a technique
表示，这是一种技术
that all these persistent collection
所有这些持久的收藏
implementations use so if you look at
实现，所以如果你看
this implementation you'd have the same
这个实现你会有相同的
symbol at depth as before you check if
深度与您检查之前一样
the bit is set or not and if it's not
该位是否设置，如果没有设置
set then you turn optional empty it's
设置然后将可选空
not present but then you have a
不存在但是你有一个
an operation which says how do I index
表示我如何编制索引的操作
into this array but all you do is you
进入这个数组，但是你所要做的就是你
essentially chop off the bitmap for that
从本质上来说，将位图砍掉
for all the bits before the symbol
对于符号之前的所有位
you're interested in in count the number
您有兴趣算数
of bits using bit count and then there's
使用位数计算的位数，然后
your index into your array quite nice
您对数组的索引非常好
and the reason why this can be
以及为什么可以这样
implemented efficiently in Java is
用Java有效实现的是
because integer bit count is an
因为整数位数是
intrinsic and that that compiles down to
内在的，然后编译成
a pop count instruction on x86 and
x86上的弹出计数指令
before that was intrinsic ID in the jdk
之前是jdk中的固有ID
these collections were a lot slower
这些收集速度要慢得多
because they had to do a lot of bit
因为他们不得不做很多事情
twiddling going on I get I get to this
我继续说下去
point later on hopefully there's a lot
希望以后有很多
more we can do to optimize these things
我们可以做更多的事情来优化这些东西
so I think this is a better
所以我觉得这样比较好
representation as I said the space is
正如我所说的，空间是
required only for present nodes using a
仅对于使用
bitmap and that's made possible with
位图，这使得它成为可能
hotspot optimizations there's further
热点优化还有更多
refinements you can do here and
您可以在这里进行细化
trade-offs sub nodes and entries could
权衡子节点和条目可以
be separated for more cache friendly
分开以提高缓存友好性
traversal stained or fur talked about
遍历染色或谈论毛皮
this in his champ work and hash codes
这在他的冠军作品和哈希码中
could be cached as well I wasn't caching
也可以缓存，我没有缓存
hash codes here as all sorts of
哈希码在这里是各种各样的
trade-offs and experiments we can try
我们可以尝试的权衡和实验
and the API is slightly different so if
和API略有不同，所以如果
I have a persistent map API it might
我有一个永久的地图API，可能
have a familiar for each might have a
每个人都有一个熟悉的地方
get that returns null or optional it's
得到返回null或可选的
up to you but the put method instead of
由您决定，但是put方法而不是
returning the the previous value of null
返回null的前一个值
it might have to return a new map
它可能必须返回新地图
because I'm I'm not modifying the
因为我不是在修改
existing map I'm returning a new map
现有地图我要返回新地图
with the same things as the previous one
与上一个相同
but the new entry inside it and the same
但是里面的新条目和相同
for remove in terms of removing
就删除而言
something so the API is actually
因此，API实际上是
slightly different here to what you
这里和你有些不同
might get with a hash map
可能带有哈希图
so although there's modifying methods
所以虽然有修改方法
return a new collection the
返回一个新的收藏
implementation will actually share
实施将实际共享
structure underneath and to do this
下面的结构并执行此操作
efficiently when we're building we need
我们在建设时高效地需要
we need mutable builders to construct in
我们需要可变的构建器来构建
a confined manner so what we want is a
受限的方式，所以我们想要的是
really when you're building something up
真的，当你建立东西时
you want to confine this to a closure or
您想将其限制为闭包或
a Fred so it doesn't escape out and then
一个弗雷德，所以它不会逃脱，然后
when you're done you construct them
完成后，您就可以构建它们
freeze and you've got an immutable thing
冻结，你有一个不变的东西
and closure has this con ocean of
和关闭有这个海洋
building I'm not sure about Scala it may
大厦我不确定Scala可能
well do as well so I'm going to show
做得好，所以我要展示
some demos now now let's see how
现在进行一些演示让我们看看如何
successful this will be actually before
成功，这实际上是之前
I go and did anybody have any quick
我去了，有人快吗
questions on the explanations no well
关于解释的问题不好
good okay so I'm gonna wing it a bit
很好，我要加一点翅膀
here let's see how this goes so first of
在这里，让我们先来看一下
all I'm going to I'm going to run J
我要去的一切我要去办J
shell start this up okay this is
壳启动这个好吧，这是
actually J shell running Java 10 or 18
实际上是运行Java 10或18的J shell
dot free as we like to call it nowadays
如今我们喜欢称它为无点
I'm not going to get into discussion on
我不打算讨论
version numbers so we can use var
版本号，因此我们可以使用var
so I've there's a github project here I
所以我这里有一个github项目
sent a link to this is all online on
发送了一个链接到这是所有在线
github you can check this out and play
github，你可以检查出来玩
with it yourself and get an idea of how
自己动手，并了解如何
these structures work what I've written
这些结构可以像我写的那样工作
is buggy it's not performant but its
是越野车，它不是高性能的，但它的
function enough to experiment with so
功能足以尝试
you finally bugs in it send me a push
您终于发现其中的错误，这给了我很大的推动力
request pull the request and I will I
请求拉请求，我将
will accept it and fix things it's in
会接受它并修复其中的内容
the open open JDK saying licenses open
公开公开JDK说许可证公开
JDK so if I just create a very simple
JDK所以如果我只是创建一个非常简单的
map like so VAR m equals P map valve
像VAR m等于P映射阀
like that I can visualize this like so
这样我可以像这样想象
what that's going to do it's going to
这将要做什么
look at the structure it's going to
看看它要去的结构
create a dot file convert the dot file
创建一个点文件转换该点文件
to SVG and load it up in the browser if
SVG并将其加载到浏览器中
I can get my okay so here we go this is
我可以没事的，所以我们在这里是
our first visualization of the map it's
我们对地图的第一次可视化
not very interesting
不太有趣
but it's useful to explain what's going
但是解释发生的事情很有用
this I have one entry in my map I have
我在地图上有一个条目
the key of one and a value of one I
一的关键和一的价值
haven't one node at the top here with a
这里的顶部没有一个节点
bitmap that says of 32 values so this is
位图表示32个值，所以这是
this is my bitmap I showed earlier the
这是我之前显示的位图
int the int bitmap and it's and it's
int int位图，它是和
essentially got one bit set the size of
基本上设置了一个大小
one and there's a prefix here for one
一个，这里有一个前缀
the key is one any any integer value
键为任意整数值之一
under 2 to the 16 is actually the hash
在2到16之间实际上是哈希
code is itself essentially that's it
代码本身就是这样
that's what you need to know here so but
这就是您需要在这里知道的
the hash code of 1 is 1 and so I have a
1的哈希码是1，所以我有一个
prefix here the first applied bits of 1
在此处为1的第一个应用位添加前缀
and the total hash is this going from
总哈希是从
least significant bit to most
最低至最高
significant bit here so does that make
重要的是，这也使
sense
感
so I can add some more here so I can
所以我可以在这里添加更多
visualize two things instead so we can
可视化两件事，所以我们可以
we can put another value here like so
我们可以像这样放置另一个值
and we can visualize two things so now
我们可以想象两件事，所以现在
we get now we get the previous map and
现在我们得到以前的地图，
the new map like so so we still have one
这样的新地图，所以我们仍然有一个
node 1 node depth we have the previous
节点1节点深度
map with the key of 1 to 1 and we have a
用1到1的键映射，我们有一个
new map with 1 &amp; 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 2 so that's the
1＆1＆2＆2的新地图，所以
Muta book there's no structural sharing
Muta书没有结构性分享
here because we were at the same depth
在这里，因为我们在同一深度
here which we essentially got the the
在这里，我们基本上得到了
two arrays can't be shared so we had to
两个数组无法共享，所以我们不得不
structurally share when we when we go
当我们走时在结构上分享
down in terms of nodes now that but you
现在节点数量下降，但是您
can see here the prefix here is
可以看到这里的前缀是
different the hash is different so for
不同的哈希值是不同的
that so it's very easy to visualize and
这样很容易可视化
play around with these things so I can
玩这些东西，所以我可以
show a few more complex examples here
在这里显示一些更复杂的例子
okay so here is here is a good example
好吧，这是一个很好的例子
of what I reckon you'll see that so i
我认为您会看到的，所以我
zoom in here's an example of building up
放大这里是建立示例
a persistent map and this is a common
永久地图，这是常见的
thing you might do in least jdk code you
你可能会做的事情至少是jdk代码
might have the the symbols for your
可能有您的符号
primitive types in byte code BD fi and
字节码BD fi和的原始类型
so forth mapping to the box types and
依此类推映射到框类型
that you might create a map for that so
你可以为此创建一个地图
what I'm doing here is I'm creating an
我在这里正在做的是
empty map rather than putting my first
空的地图，而不是把我的第一
entry in my second entry for identity
在我的第二个条目中输入身份
for veggie all immutably so I'm creating
都是素食，所以我在创造
all these structures and throwing them
所有这些结构并扔给他们
away and throwing away creating all
走开，扔掉创造一切
these structure until I get the one I
这些结构，直到我得到一个
want that's not the particularly
希望那不是特别的
efficient way of doing it but we can
有效的方法，但是我们可以
visualize this and see what see what
想像一下，看看会看到什么
happened so I'll just run this test here
发生了，所以我将在这里运行此测试
and it should do the same thing as
它应该做与
before
之前
okay so this is getting harder to see
好吧，这变得越来越难看
can you see that not really but the
你能看到不是真的吗
point being is that this actually
关键是，这实际上
there's no collisions here there's no
这里没有碰撞，那里没有碰撞
sub knows it all maps at one level deep
潜艇知道所有这些地图都深一层
here and we can see the various prefixes
在这里，我们可以看到各种前缀
and hash codes here and we can see the
和哈希码在这里，我们可以看到
top node here as there's nine entries
顶部节点，因为有九个条目
and there's nine bits set in my bitmap
我的位图中设置了九位
like that and there's no there's no
这样，没有就没有
conflicting prefixes here so we're not
此处的前缀冲突，因此我们不会
getting down any any level deep so
深入到任何水平
that's actually quite a nice property I
这实际上是一个很好的财产
just packed in essentially eighteen
基本上只包装了十八个
eighteen entries in my object array
我的对象数组中有18个条目
knows no spare space if you're using a
如果您使用的是
hash map you probably need to get you'd
您可能需要获取的哈希图
have to have a hash table a bucket size
必须有一个散列表大小的哈希表
about thirty two to stop the collisions
大约三十二停止碰撞
so you're already saving some space here
所以你已经在这里节省了一些空间
and it's all nicely cache coherent
这一切都很好地缓存了一致性
because it's all in a single array so
因为它们都在一个数组中
when I traverse that I'm going to get
当我穿越时我会得到
the prefetching working as well the only
预取工作以及唯一的
thing I don't have in here is I'm not
我在这里没有的东西是我不是
sharing and not storing that I'm not
分享而不是存储我不是
caching the hash codes so I'm going to
缓存哈希码，所以我要
take a hit in terms of time when I when
当我什么时候受到时间的打击
I compare my hash codes but there's ways
我比较我的哈希码，但是有办法
to cash flows too so that's an example
也有现金流，这就是一个例子
there let me show you the concept of
在那里让我向您展示
building instead so I showed it building
建筑，所以我展示了它
structurally immutably and I'm throwing
结构上一成不变，我抛出
away arrays every time I put here as
每次我放在这里作为
they create a new one so creating some
他们创造了一个新的，所以创造了一些
garbage collection here but I can do the
垃圾收集在这里，但我可以做
same instead by saying P map of and
而不是说和的P图
instead I get it essentially what I call
相反，我基本上得到了我所说的
a builder a P map builder here and all P
一个P的地图生成器，以及所有P
map builder does is has a put method on
地图构建器所做的是在put方法上
it all I can do is add stuff to the map
我所能做的就是向地图添加内容
and I'm doing it in a closure here and I
我在这里封闭地做着
want to confine this builder so it only
只想限制这个生成器
operates within this closure and within
在此闭包内和内部运行
the same thread if I operate it in
如果我在同一线程操作
another thread it will throw a legal
另一个线程将抛出一个合法的
state exception if I somehow cache it
状态异常，如果我以某种方式缓存它
outside the closure by storing it in an
通过将其存储在一个封闭的外部
array or in a field or something like
数组或字段或类似的东西
that and operate on it when I'm outside
并在外面时对其进行操作
the closure it will float legal state
关闭它将浮动合法状态
search and something I'd nicely confined
搜索和我会很好地限制的东西
this thing and then I can mute ibly
这个东西，然后我可以静音
update this safely because I know no
安全地更新此内容，因为我不知道
fred's will will turn on it and I know
弗雷德的遗嘱将打开它，我知道
that if I if it
那如果我
so nothing will happen bad will happen
所以不会发生坏事
to afterwards and this is quite a
到后来，这是一个相当
powerful concept we did the same thing
强大的概念，我们做了同样的事情
with the stack Walker API if you've ever
如果您曾经使用过堆栈Walker API
used this to get stacks and traversing
用它来获取栈和遍历
the frames using the stream API in a
在框架中使用流API的帧
closure and in a confined way using
封闭并以密闭方式使用
closure like this and I think this is a
这样的封闭，我认为这是一个
very interesting pattern because I can
非常有趣的模式，因为我可以
build up something mutable and not throw
建立一些可变的东西而不扔
away and create a bunch of garbage and
离开并制造一堆垃圾，
once the closure finishes I freeze of
一旦关闭完成我冻结
collection and it becomes immutable
集合，它变得不可变
again I'm doing some interesting tricks
我又在做一些有趣的把戏
with JD some misc unsafe here if you
与JD在这里有些杂项不安全，如果您
want to look at the code I'm actually
想看看我实际上的代码
rather than doing a copy of the data I'm
而不是复制我的数据
transforming the class header from
从转换头
something that I can write on in terms
我可以用术语写的东西
of fields to something that is the same
到相同的领域
structure with final fields later on if
如果稍后有最终字段的结构
you want to look at the code you
你想看看你的代码
shouldn't be doing this at home but this
不应该在家里做这个
is these are the kind of tricks we can
这些是我们可以运用的技巧吗
do in the JDK and we as long as we can
在JDK中做，只要我们可以
test it and we trust our code we can we
测试它，我们相信我们的代码，我们可以
can do these types of tricks and and and
可以做这些技巧，并且和
no one else can do these types of tricks
没有其他人可以做这些类型的把戏
outside that's an advantage to us and
外面对我们有利
that's one reason why these things are
这就是为什么这些东西是
in other interest to me is we can
对我来说，其他好处是我们可以
optimize the heck out of these things
优化这些东西
anyone can write these things on top of
任何人都可以在上面写这些东西
a JD get reasonable efficiency I think
我认为JD获得合理的效率
we can do a better job if a in the JDK
如果在JDK中，我们可以做得更好
itself so that's one advantage so I
本身就是一个优势，所以我
showed that I can we can just run that
表明我可以运行
two just to show that it will build a
两个只是为了表明它将建立一个
map like so okay same thing as before
地图像以前一样好
it's no different
没什么两样
I get the same structure out immutable
我得到不变的相同结构
structure there okay let's show
那里的结构好吧，让我们展示一下
something more complex let's show this
让我们更复杂一点
one here so I'm I'm not building
一个在这里，所以我不在
efficiently here but I'm just creating a
有效地在这里，但我只是在创建一个
bunch of entries of fruit to color like
一堆水果要变色
this and I'm going to visualize the map
这，我将可视化地图
I built but I'm also going to visualize
我建好了，但我也要形象化
the one with blue the blueberry entry
蓝色的蓝莓入口
removed let's see what happens
删除让我们看看会发生什么
yeah so this is going to create quite a
是的，所以这将创造一个
big map here so if we just yep is quite
大地图在这里，所以如果我们只是是相当
big but if you notice here we're getting
很大，但是如果您注意到这里，我们将会
some structural sharing between the two
两者之间的一些结构性共享
maps because we've got a sub node that
映射，因为我们有一个子节点
conflicts on the first PI bit prefix so
第一个PI位前缀存在冲突，因此
the first fight bit prefix here both
第一个战斗位前缀都在这里
banana and plum share the thirst by bit
香蕉和李子一点点地渴
prefix of 0 0 0 0 0 so we can
0 0 0 0 0的前缀，所以我们可以
structurally share that between the two
在结构上在两者之间分享
maps that we modified so this map will
我们修改过的地图，因此此地图将
have so it has blueberry in but there's
有，所以里面有蓝莓，但是有
only one blueberry here there's not in
这里只有一个蓝莓没有
the other map we removed it but we can
其他地图我们将其删除，但我们可以
structurally share this sub mode layer
在结构上共享此子模式层
here so when you got more complex layers
这样，当您获得更复杂的图层时
there's more structural sharing you can
您可以进行更多结构性分享
actually do here and this is interesting
实际上在这里做，这很有趣
this is makes it also it makes it easier
这不仅使它更容易
to split because there's a natural split
分裂是因为自然分裂
point both in the array and this one
既指向数组又指向这个
here too so hopefully that gets it
这里也是如此希望得到它
across a little bit here we can see that
穿过一点，我们可以看到
the prefix here we now have 2 5 bits
前缀这里我们现在有2 5位
here the first 5 bits and the second
这里的前5位和第二位
five bits or two symbols and we can see
五位或两个符号，我们可以看到
that it's always a prefix of the total
它始终是总数的前缀
hash code here when you're comparing
比较时在这里哈希代码
these these values
这些这些价值
so we can do something more complex so
所以我们可以做一些更复杂的事情
let's see so here's his system
让我们来看看，这是他的系统
properties so system properties is it
属性，是系统属性吗
essentially it's a map of all the system
本质上是所有系统的地图
properties in the JDK maybach so let's
JDK maybach中的属性，让我们
visualize this and see what this looks
形象地看这看
like this would be a more complex one
这样会更复杂
okay so you get an idea of the structure
好，这样您就可以了解结构
here there's more sub nodes happening
这里有更多的子节点
here let's scroll all the way down yeah
在这里让我们一直向下滚动
so we see a prefix here shared prefix
所以我们在这里看到一个前缀共享前缀
and other symbols down and so forth but
和其他符号向下等等
it only gets down to about the depth of
它只能下降到大约
two maybe three at the end here so it's
最后两个，也许三个
still quite shallow so if you're going
还很浅所以如果你要
to look up something it's going to
查找它要去的东西
traverse a little bit but it's not going
横穿一点，但是没有走
to traverse too deeply and that's why
穿越得太深，这就是为什么
it's almost constant time what you're
这几乎是恒定的时间
doing so there's a good structural
这样做有一个很好的结构
sharing here and reasonable efficiency
在这里分享和合理的效率
in terms of access you're probably not
在访问方面，您可能不是
going to be a well sized hashmap here
这里将是一个大小合适的哈希图
but I'd argue that potentially hashmap
但我认为潜在的哈希图
will take up more memory see potentially
将占用更多内存，可能会出现
trading off space and time here a little
在这里交换空间和时间
bit but very actually good compromise I
有点，但实际上是非常好的妥协
don't think if you're using these things
不要以为你在用这些东西
most people won't notice or won't need
大多数人不会注意到或不需要
the extra performance that's my theory
这是我的理论的额外表现
anyway I don't know if it's entirely
无论如何，我不知道这是否完全是
true would have to verify that we'd have
true将必须验证我们是否拥有
to do good performance tests on these
对这些进行良好的性能测试
things too but they just to express as
事情也一样，但它们只是表达为
showing a good good good set of
表现出很好的一套
properties here we can look at some more
这里的属性我们可以看看更多
degenerate cases here so what happens if
在这里退化案例，如果发生什么情况
you have a collision so two hash codes
你有冲突，所以两个哈希码
to two entries two keys share the same
到两个条目，两个键共享相同的
hash code what do you do then so I have
哈希码你怎么办所以我有
in here an int key which essentially
在这里一个int键
sets the hash code of these two things
设置这两件事的哈希码
to zero so I have an entity whose key is
零，所以我有一个实体，其键是
one and an int key is key is two but
一个和一个int键是键，但是两个
their hash codes are the same I'm just
他们的哈希码和我一样
concocting this there with one and two
用一和二炮制
so in this case we have a collision here
所以在这种情况下，我们在这里发生碰撞
signified by a red box so what do we do
用红色框表示，那么我们该怎么办
when we have a collision we could use a
当我们发生碰撞时，我们可以使用
linked list we could use a red black
链表，我们可以使用红色黑色
tree like we do in hashmap today or we
就像我们今天在哈希图中所做的树，还是我们
could change for the hash algorithm and
可以更改为哈希算法，并且
go and use the same ham T structure with
去和使用相同的火腿T结构
a different hash code algorithm to and
和的哈希码算法不同
go down as lots of options we can
尽可能多的选择
experiment with so let's look at another
尝试一下，让我们看看另一个
let's look at a generate case of how
让我们看看如何
deep we can go down in the tree so what
我们可以深入到树上
I'm doing here is I'm concocting
我在这里做我在炮制
integers that just so happen but I know
整数就是这样，但我知道
the hash code algorithm internally to
内部的哈希码算法
create the Hat to create the actual hash
创建帽子以创建实际的哈希
code values I'm using in my map so I'm
我在地图中使用的代码值，所以我
creating I want to set the two top level
创建我想设置两个顶级
bits
位
remember it's fight it's six symbols
记住它是战斗，这是六个符号
with the two two top-level bits most
最多两个两个顶级位
significant bits only at the end setting
有效位仅在结束设置时
their values I'm also setting their
他们的价值观，我也在设定
values here because the hash code is is
值，因为哈希码是
slightly shifted a bit so I'm but way
稍微移动了一点，所以我只是
I'd calculate the hash code is the way
我会计算哈希码是这样
you do it in hash map you shift the hash
你在哈希图中完成，你转移哈希
code by sixty and XOR it with itself so
通过六十码进行编码，然后对其进行异或运算
I want to I want to cancel out the ones
我想我想取消那些
and just have the hash code to the top
然后将哈希码放在顶部
top two significant bits here just to
这两个重要位只是为了
show the degenerate case and so what
显示退化的情况，那又如何
happens here we get one two three four
发生在这里我们得到一二三四
fire depth of six when we get our four
当我们得到四个时，射击深度为六个
values right down at the bottom so if
值直接在底部，所以如果
you're traversing this structure you
您正在遍历此结构
have to go down sit all the way down all
必须一直坐下去
the way down not very cache coherent not
下降的方式不是非常快缓存连贯
particularly very efficient inefficient
效率非常低下
but you're bounded but a level of 60
但是你被限制在60级
you're not going to go further and
你不会走得更远，
further so if you're writing if you're
更进一步，如果您正在写作，
adding algorithms for this and you don't
为此添加算法，您不会
want to use recursion you can allocate a
要使用递归，您可以分配一个
stack on the heap of just six it's very
堆在只有六个的堆上
very nice property that I mean we see
非常好的属性，我的意思是我们看到了
the values in there so that's the worst
那里的价值，所以这是最糟糕的
case you can possibly get which I'd
如果你可能得到我想要的
argue is is not going to be very common
争论不是很普遍
ok I think that's it if you want to
好的，我想就是这样
check out the code and have some fun
签出代码，玩得开心
with this or send me fixes and that I'd
与此相关或向我发送修复程序，而我
be very interested on on that stuff okay
对这些东西很感兴趣
so to summarize so I think unmodifiable
总结一下，所以我认为无法修改
is a reasonable abstraction for mutable
是可变的合理抽象
but not immutable I hope I persuaded you
但不是一成不变的，我希望我能说服你
that for efficient immutable collections
高效的不可变集合
we need persistent collections without
我们需要持久的收集而没有
sort of arguing guava gets you so far
有点争吵番石榴让你走到现在
it's reasonable but I think we could do
这是合理的，但我认为我们可以做到
better and other languages and platforms
更好的语言和其他平台
actually do do better and sets maps
实际做得更好并设置地图
vectors using ham teas have been proven
使用火腿茶的载体已被证明
to be effective in these libraries and
在这些库中有效
platforms I think so they've proven
我认为平台已经证明了
their worth so what about Java this is
他们的价值，那么Java是什么
where it comes a bit speculative and
有点投机性
more my opinion I think we'll definitely
我的看法更多，我认为我们一定会
continuing to prove on unmodifiable in
继续证明不可修改
the JDK and Stewart marks is already
JDK和Stewart标记已经
working on some stuff like this he's
他在做这样的事情
already got one thing in review on core
已经对核心进行了一件事的审查
libs dev and open JDK and there's some
libs dev并打开JDK，其中有一些
other stuff in the pipe to make some
管子里的其他东西
good improvements here but what about
这里有很好的改进，但是呢
say selective sedimentation I love that
说选择性沉淀我爱那个
word that's a mark Reinhold word but he
这个词是一个标记Reinhold这个词，但是他
uses that we have the luxury to look
使用我们有豪华的外观
outside there other languages and
外面还有其他语言和
platforms and see what they're doing
平台，看看他们在做什么
stand back ponder them and take the best
退后一步思考他们，并采取最好的
bits from each could we do that with
每个人都可以用
persistent collections in the Java
Java中的持久性集合
platform
平台
perhaps we could a claim I say it's
也许我们可以说我说是
possible to optimize these collections
可以优化这些集合
very very aggressively with internal
非常非常积极地与内部
api's hotspot and safely contained
api的热点并被安全地包含
unsafe mechanisms but I talked about
不安全的机制，但我谈到了
when I was doing building there are
当我做建筑的时候
there there are ways that we could
有很多方法可以
leverage more intrinsic as I showed you
正如我向您展示的那样，更充分地利用
about pop count at the JVM a less talk
关于JVM的弹出计数的讨论较少
by Stein dauther he talked about multi
Stein dauther讲了多
maps and he was using AVX style
地图，他使用的是AVX样式
instructions to do bit manipulation of
指令进行位操作
these multi maps to make them efficient
这些多张地图，使它们高效
as well as stuff we can do there too
以及我们在那里也可以做的事情
there's a lot of research here but my
这里有很多研究，但是我的
claim is that we can optimize these
声称是我们可以优化这些
things like no one else on top of the
像其他人一样的事情
JDK can optimum
JDK可以优化
today and that is the end of my
今天，到此为止
presentation and there's some references
演示，还有一些参考
at the back here I'll upload this
在这里的后面，我将上传
presentation and tweet about it
演示文稿和关于它的推文
there's some references to some of the
有一些参考
papers write about these data structures
论文写了这些数据结构
as especially like to recommend stein
特别喜欢推荐斯坦
daughter's thesis I think he's done some
女儿的论文，我想他做了一些
interesting work build a gun ban on
有趣的工作建立了枪支禁令
Bagwell and if you're interested look at
Bagwell，如果您有兴趣的话，请看
closures vector and look at the the
闭包向量，然后看
stuff in Scala the implementations of VR
Scala中有关VR实现的内容
BB vectors as well and there's an
BB向量也有
interesting one at the end it's it's
最后有趣的是
using these hash hash hash array mapped
使用这些哈希将哈希数组映射为哈希
rice for concurrent collections and as
大米用于同时收集和
by Pro kopeck are very interesting
Pro kopeck的作品非常有趣
leveraging these things for concurrent
利用这些东西并发
collections which have similar
具有相似的收藏
characteristics to concurrent skip lists
并发跳过列表的特征
okay I think I'm done any questions no
好吧，我想我已经完成了任何问题，否
questions
问题
you all understood that right okay thank
你们都知道，好的，谢谢
you
您
[Applause]
[掌声]